What if the slipper didn't fit?
Cinderella III: A Twist in Time is a animation, romance,
family film directed by Frank Nissen.
When Lady Tremaine steals the Fairy Godmother's wand and changes history, it's
up to Cinderella to restore the timeline and reclaim her prince.
Cinderella (voice), played by Jennifer Hale.
Prince Charming (voice), played by Christopher Daniel Barnes.
Lady Tremaine (voice), played by Susanne Blakeslee.
Anastasia (voice), played by Tress MacNeille.
The Fairy Godmother / Drizella (voice), played by Russi Taylor.
The King (voice), played by Andre Stojka.
Cinderella III: A Twist in Time is a 2007 American animated direct-to-video musical fantasy film
produced by DisneyToon Studios and distributed by Buena Vista Home Entertainment.
Directed by Frank Nissen from a screenplay written by Dan Berendsen, Margaret Heidenry, Colleen Ventimilia, and Eddie Guerlain, it is the
third installment in Disney's Cinderella trilogy and a sequel to Cinderella (1950) and Cinderella II: Dreams Come True (2002).
In Cinderella III: A Twist in Time, set one year after the first film, Cinderella struggles with the
effects of a time-reversing spell cast by Lady Tremaine to prevent her from marrying the Prince.
The film's voice cast consists of Jennifer Hale, C.
Barnes, Susanne Blakeslee, Tress MacNeille, Russi Taylor, and Andre Stojka, most of whom continue to
replace the 1950 film's cast by reprising their roles from Cinderella II: Dreams Come True.
Cinderella III: A Twist in Time was completed over the
course of two years, from 2004 to 2006.
Inspired by Anastasia's romantic subplot introduced in Dreams Come True, A Twist in Time expands upon her reformation into a more
sympathetic villain, while the writers updated Cinderella and the Prince's personalities to be more appealing to modern audiences.
Although none of Cinderella's original animators were involved in the sequel, the filmmakers
referenced the 1950 film and Disney's Animation Research Library for research and inspiration.
The film was one of Disney's last direct-to-video sequels before
the studio pivoted towards making original content.
A Twist in Time was also the final project produced by DisneyToon Studios Australia, with
Disney dissolving various departments while the film was still in production.
Cinderella III: A Twist in Time was released
direct-to-video on February 6, 2007.
Unlike most of Disney's direct-to-video sequels, it received generally positive reviews from critics, who deemed it a vast
improvement over its immediate predecessor and praised the character developments of Cinderella, the Prince, and Anastasia.
Cinderella III: A Twist in Time has grossed nearly
$93 million in home video sales.
The film explores themes of magic, fairy, cartoon, prince, musical.
The tone is emotional.